Jane Teller
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Jane Teller papers
1911-1991
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Teller, Jane
8.3 linear feet
The papers of printmaker and sculptor Jane Teller measure 8.3 linear feet and date from 1911 to 1991. The papers include biographical materials, correspondence, business records, notes, writings, three sketchbooks, sketches and prints, five scrapbooks, printed material, subject files, photographs, sound and video recordings, and motion picture film.
Provenance
The Jane Teller papers were donated by Jane Teller in 1990 and in 1991 by Walter Teller, widower of Jane Teller.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
Jane Teller (1911-1990) worked as a printmaker and sculptor primarily in New Jersey. She specialized in working with wood and studied at the Rochester Institute of Technology, Skidmore College, and Barnard College. She also attended Federal Works Progress Administration (W.P.A.) classes in New York City, studying sculpture with Aaron J. Goodelman and wood carving with Karl Nielson. She later studied welding in the studio of Ibram Lassaw. She was also a lifelong friend of photographer Aaron Siskind. In 1960, she was awarded the Mary and Gustave Kellner Prize at the National Association of Women Artists Annual Exhibition at the National Academy of Design in New York, and in 1966 the Sculpture Prize at the Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition, Philadelphia Art Alliance in Philadelphia. She exhibited mainly in New York and New Jersey and was married to author and editor Walter Teller.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of printmaker and sculptor Jane Teller measure 8.3 linear feet and date from 1911 to 1991. The papers include biographical materials, correspondence, business records, notes, writings, three sketchbooks, sketches and prints, five scrapbooks, printed material, subject files, photographs, sound and video recordings, and motion picture film.
Biographical material includes a birth certificate, school work, and passports. General correspondence includes letters from several artists including Rhys Caparn, Sue Fuller and Lee Gatch, and from art galleries, including the Museum of Modern Art, Albright-Knox Art Gallery and the Whitney Museum of American Art. Additional correspondence is found in the Subject Files.
Business records include an account book, lists of expenses and prices of art works, and sales records. Notes and writings include Teller's notes about art and travel, artists' statements, autobiographical writings, and a compilation of many artists' statements regarding "The Nine Bean Question."
Artwork includes three sketchbooks, 30 sketches and three prints primarily depicting nature and sculpture designs.
Five scrapbooks contain clippings, exbition announcements and catalogs. Additional printed material includes magazines, exhibition announcements and catalogs, a booklet by Teller entitled Art, Age and the River, published posthumously by her husband, and a manuscript of Poems or Poetic Expressions of Sculptors, collected by L. Lamis.
Subject files are arranged by name or subject and may contain letters, photographs, and printed material. Many of the files focus on galleries and museums, including the Montclair Art Museum, the Newark Museum, Noyes Museum, Parma Gallery, the Princeton Gallery of Fine Art and the Squibb Gallery. There are also subject files for associations, travel, projects, and colleagues including Margaret K. Johnson, Reuben Kadish, Ibram Lassaw, Aaron Siskind and Dorothy Dehner.
Photographs and slides depict Teller, her friends, works, gallery installations, and travels. Also included are photographs of trees, bark, and other natural formations used by Teller in her work.
The audio-visual materials include several sound recordings, videocassettes and 16 mm motion pictures. The videocassettes include television programs in which Teller, printmaker Judith Brodsky and actor Harry Hamlin are interviewed, a retrospective at Skidmore College and a film featuring Teller speaking for the National Council on Aging. Sound recordings include two interviews and a "Talk on Malta" by Teller and Joan Needham. The 16 mm tapes are of Teller at her first Parma Gallery show.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series. Records are generally arranged by material type and chronologically thereafter.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1911-1985 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1956-1991 (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, 1961-1990 (Box 1; 5 folders)
Series 4: Notes, 1960-1987 (Box 1; 13 folders)
Series 5: Writings, 1960-1989 (Boxes 1 and 9; 5 folders)
Series 6: Artwork, circa 1950s (Boxes 1 and 9; 6 folders)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1948-1990 (Boxes 1-2; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1957-1991 (Boxes 2-3 and 9; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 9: Subject Files, 1951-1990 (Boxes 3-5; 2.5 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1934-1985 (Boxes 5-9; 2.5 linear feet)
Series 11: Audio-Visual Materials, 1952-1989 (Box 8; 0.3 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Brodsky, Judith K.; Dehner, Dorothy, 1901-; Johnson, Margaret K. (Margaret Kennard); Kadish, Reuben, 1913-; Lassaw, Ibram, 1913-2003; Siskind, Aaron; Montclair Art Museum; National Council on the Aging; Newark Museum; Noyes Museum; Parma Gallery (New York, N.Y.); Princeton Gallery of Fine Art; Squibb Gallery (Princeton, N.J.)
Subjects-Topical:
Art galleries, Commercial--New Jersey; Sculptors--New Jersey--Princeton; Sculpture, Modern--20th century--United States; Women artists--New Jersey; Printmakers--New Jersey
Types of Materials:
Interviews; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Prints; Scrapbooks; Sketches; Sketchbooks; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings; Sketchbooks; Video recordings
Names:
Caparn, Rhys, 1909-; Fuller, Sue, 1914-; Gatch, Lee, 1902-1968; Lamis, Leroy, 1925-; Albright-Knox Art Gallery; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Whitney Museum of American Art
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material,1911-1985, Series 1:; (Box 1; 4 folders)
  Biographical material dates from 1911 to 1985 and is comprised of a birth certificate, passports, report cards and resumes.
  - Certificates, Passports, Resumes, 1930-1984, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Schoolwork, 1911-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence,1956-1991, Series 2:; (Box 1; 0.3 linear feet)
  Correspondence dates from 1956 to 1991 and includes letters from Rhys Caparn, Sue Fuller and Lee Gatch. A substantial amount of correspondence is from art galleries, including the Museum of Modern Art, Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Buffalo, New York) and the Whitney Museum of American Art.
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1991, (15 folders) (Box 1, Folder 5-19)
  - Rhys Caparn, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lee Gatch, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, 1956-1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Business Records,1961-1990, Series 3:; (Box 1; 5 folders)
  Business Records date from 1961 to 1990 and include an account book, lists of expenses, prices of art works, receipts, sales records and travel receipts.
  - Account Book: Expenses and Sales, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Lists of Works and Price Lists, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Receipts, 1961-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Sales Records, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Trips, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Notes, 1960-1987, Series 4:; (Box 1; 13 folders)
  Notes date from 1960 to 1987 and include notes about frames, wood finishes and travel ideas, a notebook from a Renaissance architecture class and notes for an essay about Zoltan Buki.
  - Notes for Zoltan Buki Essay, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Lecture Notes: Talk on Malta, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - On Frames, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - On Wood Finishes, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notebook from "Renaissance Architecture" Class, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Card File: Works (Chronological), undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Card File: Works (Alphabetical), undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Regarding Photographs of Works, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Master Lists: Sculpture/Drawings, 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Trip Ideas, 1971-1986, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 37-39)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Writings,1960-1989, Series 5:; (Boxes 1, 9; 5 folders)
  Writings date from 1960 to 1989 and primarily consist of artists' staements and autobiographical writings on Teller's thought and dreams, and a compilation of many artists' statements regarding "The Nine Bean Question."
  - Writings, 1960-1984, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-44)
  - "Nine Bean Question", 1989, (Oversized item housed in box 9, folder 1) (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Oversized "Nine Bean Question", 1989, (See also box 1, folder 45) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Artwork,circa 1950s, Series 6:; (Boxes 1, 9; 6 folders)
  Artwork dates from circa 1950s and includes three sketchbooks, thirty sketches and three prints. The artwork depicts nature and sculpture designs.
  - Sketchbook, undated, (Oversized item housed in box 9, folder 2) (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Sketchbooks, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
  - Sketches, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 49-50)
  - For Stationery, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Oversized Sketchbook, undated, (See also box 1, folder 46) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Scrapbooks,1948-1990, Series 7:; (Boxes 1-2; 0.7 linear feet)
  Five scrapbooks date from 1948 to 1990 and contain clippings, exbition announcements and catalogs.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1948-1963, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 52-54)
  - Scrapbook 1, 1948-1963, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1963-1972, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-10)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1973-1983, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11-16)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1983-1988, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1983-1990, (11 folders) (Box 2, Folder 20-30)
- Printed Material,1957-1991, Series 8:; (Boxes 2-3, 9; 0.6 linear feet)
  Printed material dates from 1957 to 1991 and includes 8 issues of the magazine Scrap, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Teller and others, a booklet by Teller entitled Art, Age and the River, published posthumously by her husband, and a manuscript of Poems or Poetic Expressions of Sculptors, collected by L. Lamis.
  - Clippings, 1957-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
  - Clippings and "9 Evenings" Performance Schedule, 1966, (Oversized item housed in box 9, folder 3) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1970-1991, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 34-39)
  - "Scrap" Newspaper, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1962-1990, (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 41-46)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1964-1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1964-1989, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Booklets: Art, Age, and the River, 1991, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
  - "Poems or Poetic Expressions of Sculptors", 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Oversized Clippings and "9 Evenings" Performance Schedule, 1966, (See also box 2, folder 33) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Subject Files,1951-1990, Series 9:; (Boxes 3-5; 2.5 linear feet)
  Subject Files date from 1951 to 1990 and contain letters, photographs, and printed material about galleries and museums, including the Montclair Art Museum, the Newark Museum, Noyes Museum, Parma Gallery, the Princeton Gallery of Fine Art and the Squibb Gallery. The collection contains subject files with materials from colleagues Margaret K. Johnson, Reuben Kadish, Ibram Lassaw, Aaron Siskind and Dorothy Dehner. Other subjects include Tellers' various travels and projects.
  - Archives of American Art, 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Anne Arnold, 1961-1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Art Quest '85, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Philip H. Augerson, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Awards in the Visual Arts, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Barbara Fiedler Gallery, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Barnard College, 1960-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Berresford Gallery, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Bicentennial Graphics, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Ciba-Geigy Corporation, 1969-1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Alan Cohen, 1973-1987, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Dorothy Dehner, 1962-1990, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 25-30)
  - Disabled Artists, 1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Donnell Art Library, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Douglass Library, Rutgers University, 1981-1988, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
  - Dumont-Landis Fine Art, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1977-1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Forager House, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Friends' Central School, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Elinor Gadon, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Galerie Claude Bernard, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Gallery 100, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Franz Geierhaas, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - George School, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Thomas George, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Trip to Greece, 1966, (9 folders) (Box 3, Folder 45-53)
  - George Greene, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Yass Hakoshima Mime Theatre, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - International Association for Cultural Exchange, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - International Sculpture Center, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Janus Gallery, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Margaret K. Johnson, 1975-1988, (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 59-61)
  - Johnson and Johnson, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Virginia Jones (Texas Woman's University), 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Library for the Blind, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ibram Lassaw, 1951-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Magic Muse, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marisol, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ann McCoy, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mercer County Community College, 1979-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - M.O.M.A. Sculpture U.S.A., 1958-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Reuben Kadish, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Knoxville Museum of Art, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Montclair Art Museum, 1982-1988, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
  - National Association of Women Artists, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - National Museum of American Art, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newark Museum, 1965-1982, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - New Hope, PA, 1956-1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - New Jersey Council on the Arts, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - New Jersey State Council on the Arts Fellowship, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - New Jersey State Museum, 1965-1986, (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 20-25)
  - New Sculpture Group, 1959-1987 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Noyes Museum, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
  - The Odyssey Project, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 29-31)
  - Osgood Gallery, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Parma Gallery, 1957-1963, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 33-36)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Philadelphia Museum, 1955-1962 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Princeton Adult School, 1968-1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Princeton Art Association, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Princeton Day School, 1977-1984 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Princeton Gallery of Fine Art, 1972-1982, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 42-43)
  - Princeton University, 1987-1990, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 44-46)
  - Publications, 1962-1979 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Queens College: Paul Klapper Library, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Queenston Press, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Riverside Museum, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Rutgers Center for Innovative Printmaking, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Rutgers University, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Sculpture for Schools for the Handicapped in Mercer and Ocean Counties, N.J., 1979-1983, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - Sculptors Guild, 1961-1989, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
  - Paulette Sears, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Alvin Sher, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Aaron Siskind, 1951-1987, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Skidmore College, 1978-1989, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
  - Soho 20, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Squibb Gallery, 1972-1985, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
  - Stuart Day School, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - George Sugarman, 1959, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Temple Judea, 1968-1980 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Trenton State College, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Unitarian Church, [November] 1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1960-1964 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 1977-1988 (Box 5, Folder 26-29)
  - Woman's Art Journal, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Photographs,1934-1985, Series 10:; (Boxes 5-9; 2.5 linear feet)
  Photographs and slides date from 1934 to 1985 and depict Teller, her friends, works, gallery installations, and travels to Corfu, England, France, Italy, Japan, Malta, Mexico, North Africa, Spain, California and Utah. Also included are studies of trees, bark, and other natural formations used by Teller in her work.
  The end of the series (folders 15-19) are slide cases. They have been placed at the back of box 8 for preservation purposes.
  - Of Jane Teller, 1934-1983, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 32-37)
  - First Studio, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Studio, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Pilobolus Dance Company, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Friends, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Frieze at Vincent Beach (Cliffs) and Photographs of Friends (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Italy, 1959, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 43-45)
  - Vincent Beach with Aaron, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Yucatan, undated, (Oversized item housed in box 9, folder 4) (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Yucutan, 1973-1974, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 48-49)
  - Utah, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Arches National Park, Utah, May 1975 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Friends; Storm King, July 1976 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Tokyo, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Spain, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Burgundy Trip, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Avebury and Stonehenge with Susan Jones, May 1982 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Philadelphia Arboretum with Alan Goodheart and Joan Needham, Spring 1987 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Palms/Vineyards at Berkeley, undated (Box 5, Folder 59-60)
  - Dogwood, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Roots Prospect", undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bark, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
  - Bark ["Beech in the Woods - Marquand" and "Japanese Maple"], undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bark and Rock Formations, May 1969, (Oversized item housed in box 9, folder 5) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bark/Aaron, [January 1969?] (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Man/Photographs of Bark, [February 1969?] (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bark, [March-April 1969?], (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Art Work "Wall II"/and Bark, [May 1969?] (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bark, June 1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bark - Marquand Park, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Trip to Corfu (Olive Trees), 1970, (Oversized item housed in box 9, folder 6) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Bark, [February 1970?] (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bark [Tulip Poplar, Sycamore, Dogwood], [February 1970?] (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Bark, [Spring 1970?] (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Olive Trees, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Bark (Faces, "The Old Men"), Spring 1973 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mercer Oak - Battlefield Park, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bark, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Skull, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Installation, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Photograph Album: Works of Art, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 25-28)
  - Portfolio of Work, 1962-1985, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 29-33)
  - Works on Paper, 1970-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 34-36)
  - Maquettes of Works of Art, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Works of Art [Removed from Slide Case], circa 1973-1982, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 38-40)
  - Miscellaneous Art Works, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Works of Art: "A", undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 42-43)
  - Works of Art: "B", undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Works of Art: "C", undated, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 45-47)
  - Works of Art: "D", undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Works of Art: "F", undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Works of Art: "F", undated, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
  - Works of Art: "G", undated, (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 5-9)
  - Works of Art: "H", undated (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Works of Art: "L", undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
  - Works of Art: "H", undated, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 14-17)
  - Works of Art: "N", undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Works of Art: "O", undated, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 19-22)
  - Works of Art: "P", undated, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-28)
  - Works of Art: "Q", undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Works of Art: "R", undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Works of Art: "S", undated (Box 7, Folder 31-37)
  - Works of Art: "T", undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Works of Art: "V", undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Works of Art: "W", undated, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-7)
  - Works by Others, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Slides: Trip to Corfu, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Slides: Trips to Corfu, Utah, Japan and Watts Towers, 1970-1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Slides: Trips to New Mexico, Spain, France and England, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Slides: Trips to England and Italy, 1982 and 1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Slides: Trips to Italy, Malta, Gozo (Morocco), Slides to Draw From: A Skull and Slides for Therapy Talk (Works by Others), 1970 and 1984 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Yucutan Photographs,undated, (See also box 5, folder 47) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Bark and Rock Formations Photographs,May 1969, (See also box 6, folder 7) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Trip to Corfu (Olive Trees) Photographs,1970, (See also box 6, folder 15) (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Audio-Visual Materials,1952-1989, Series 11:; (Box 8; 0.3 linear feet)
  Audio-visual materials date from 1952 to 1989 and include sound recordings, videocassettes and 16 mm motion picture film Caparn, Rhys, 1909-. The videocassettes are of the "State of the Arts" television programs (May and November 1989), in which Teller, printmaker Judith Brodsky and actor Harry Hamlin are interviewed, a retrospective at Skidmore College and a film entitled "The Sixth Sense" in which Teller speaks for the National Council on Aging. The audiocassettes include a "Talk on Malta" by Teller and Joan Needham and interviews for New Jersey Public TV and Princeton, New Jersey WPRB. The 16 mm tapes are of Teller at her first Parma Gallery show in 1952.
  - Audiocassettes: Interview, Princeton, N.J. WPRB and Interview, N.J. Public Television, 1974 and 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Audiocassette: "Talk on Malta" with Jane and Joan [Needham], 1985 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 16 mm Motion Picture: Jane Teller at First Parma Gallery Show, 1952, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - 1/2" Videotapes: Smithkline Beckman "The Sixth Sense" and Jane Teller Retrospective, Skidmore College, Fall 1984 and 1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1/2" Videotapes: "State of the Arts" #220 and #576, May 16, 1989 and November 26, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 14)